<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lost on null pointer</title><link>/tags/lost/</link><description>Recent content in lost on null pointer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2021 - Bernardo Meurer</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:54:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/lost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Lost Ark</title><link>/posts/the-lost-ark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:54:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/the-lost-ark/</guid><description>I was 18 when I moved to Lisbon. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really sure who I wanted to be, and I mean that quite literally. I was aware that, having just left my home country, I had a chance to choose who I wanted to be, in a sense. Of course I couldn&amp;rsquo;t just throw away all my baggage and persona, a lot of it was going to be part of who I was no matter what, but somehow it felt like a chance to pick new hobbies, new habits, things like that.</description><content>&lt;p>I was 18 when I moved to Lisbon. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really sure who I wanted to be, and I
mean that quite literally. I was aware that, having just left my home country, I
had a chance to choose who I wanted to be, in a sense. Of course I couldn&amp;rsquo;t just
throw away all my baggage and persona, a lot of it was going to be part of who I
was no matter what, but somehow it felt like a chance to pick new hobbies, new
habits, things like that. I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure how I chose to collect vinyl
records and make audio a hobby, in hindsight it was the union of a lot of things
that I loved deeply: music, analog circuitry, DIY&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, woodworking, collecting,
and on it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I quickly fell in love with the hobby, I&amp;rsquo;d spend my weekends going to record
stores in Lisbon looking for whatever record I was obsessed with that week&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>,
and most of my free time during the week went into reading about amplifier
design and things like that. Being a software developer I quickly turned those
projects into increasingly large amounts of analog-digital Frankenstein madness.
It was a whole lot of fun, and I look back at that time with a deep sense of
nostalgia.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="./images/turntable.jpg" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >My initial setup&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Sadly all good things must end, and that was definitely true for my time in
Lisbon. I had grown increasingly frustrated with the university I was attending,
and I had slowly become completely intolerant to the racism I had directed
towards me by many Portuguese&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. I was depressed, because school was deeply
unfulfilling, and because I felt that I had to work hard at hiding my
nationality and culture in order to be respected or liked by a large portion of
my peers. I was done with all that, and it was time to go somewhere else, so I
did.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="./images/packing-up.jpg" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >Packing up&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>I decided to move to the US, to Santa Barbara in particular, and with the help
of many friends I had set up my move fairly quickly. One question, however,
remained: How to get all this fragile and expensive audio across the Atlantic
and to my new house in California. Luckily my girlfriend at the time worked in
the art business and had some experience shipping things like that to the US;
she hooked me up with a great freight company and problem solved. I sent
everything with the company, except my record crate, which I was too scared and
too attached to send on a long, shaky, trip like that. Those would need another
solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Right about the time that I was beginning to lose hope, and when I thought that
I was going to have to leave them behind, my mother offered a solution. A good
friend of hers had recently moved to Lisbon, and had offered to take my records
back to Brazil with her on her next trip back home in a couple weeks. I packaged
my records and went to her house, showed her how to lock/unlock the case, and
asked her not to lay the carrying case on it&amp;rsquo;s side, records should be stored
upright. She cooked us lunch, we chatted, and then I was on my way, happy that I
had found a trustworthy warden to herd my collection across the ocean.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I got back to Brazil I immediately contacted her to get my records back,
but got no answer. She eventually blocked me on WhatsApp and told my mother she
couldn&amp;rsquo;t bring them because the case was too heavy. The case had stayed in
Lisbon, I had broken up with my girlfriend who lived there, the few friends I
had in the city had moved away. They were lost, I had placed my trust in the
wrong person. I was heartbroken, that case represented so much effort and love,
and it was simply gone, I would have to start over.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moving into my house in Santa Barbara was a stark change of scenery. I went from
living in a spacious studio in Lisbon, with a view I had grown to enjoy and a
balcony I had grown to love, to the smallest room I had ever seen, in a house so
close to the highway it shakes when a truck passed by. In addition to that I
quickly discovered that being under 21 in America means it&amp;rsquo;s illegal for you to
engage in any of the social activities you&amp;rsquo;re used to as a foreigner, you cannot
go to bars, you cannot enjoy a beer at the end of a long day. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a great
start, I missed the freedom I had had all my life; being 20 in America feels
like being 13 in Brazil, and I swiftly discovered that the maturity of my peers
mirrored that, for the most part.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="./images/balcony.jpg" />
&lt;figcaption class="center" >My beloved balcony view&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>I tried setting up my turntable in my room, even though I only had one record
in my new collection&lt;sup id="fnref:4">&lt;a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t possible. The vibrations from the
highway were so pronounced that it caused the needle to move around, it would
skip grooves, or just sounds like garbage whenever a truck or the train passed
by. I was so frustrated I packaged everything back in their respective boxes and
placed it in a remote corner of the house where I would positively forget about
their existence. That never quite happen, the amplifier box that I hid under the
sofa created a pronounced bump on the cushion, a mildly annoying reminder of the
passion I had left behind. Much like my equipment, the sofa quickly felt into
disuse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was all about two years ago, and now I find myself in a similar situation
that I did in Lisbon. I&amp;rsquo;ve been utterly unable to form meaningful relationships
here in the US&lt;sup id="fnref:5">&lt;a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, and I&amp;rsquo;m convinced my concept of a friend is somehow
incompatible with its American counterpart. I am, again, disappointed in my
studies as well. I thought Computer Science was the right major for me, given
that&amp;rsquo;s what I do in my day job and I love it, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been more
wrong about that, it&amp;rsquo;s a remarkably boring major. I can&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder where
exactly did I go wrong to end up back where I started, and I do not know the
answer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amid all this, my mother and her husband took a trip to Europe, they were going
to Spain, Morocco, and finally Portugal. I had been so frustrated in my attempts
to communicate with my mother&amp;rsquo;s friend who held the records that it took me a
while to realize what an opportunity this was. Luckily my mother is always at
least two steps ahead of me, and had somehow arranged with her rogue friend to
retrieve my records. She succeeded, and brought them back with her to Brazil,
where they now wait safely for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure through what mechanisms this happened, but somehow this
gave me a tremendously clear goal at a time where I felt like life had turned
into a Maelstrom that was slowly engulfing me, like a lion desperately confused
chasing after zebras in the savannah. Suddenly I knew which direction to swim
in, I had zeroed in on my prey and I was ready to conquer it. It was the first
time in months I had felt centered, with a clear goal. I had to get them back,
sit down, and listen to my favorite record&lt;sup id="fnref:6">&lt;a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t achieved that goal yet, but somehow just having this mundane victory
to look forward to helped me climb out of the hole that I had dug myself into. I
can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel that the records rescued me more than I rescued them.
Somehow this entity of what I thought was my past has come back to help me cope
with the present, and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait until I have them back; until I have my hobby
back.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>This might be surprising to the uninitiated, but there is a lot of DIY
projects around audio amplifiers and speakers.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2">
&lt;p>I once went to every single record store within 100 miles looking for a
Stockhausen record, eventually surrendering to getting it on Discogs.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:3">
&lt;p>I am Brazilian, and a portion of the Portuguese population holds a deep
grudge against us that I have a hard time comprehending. It&amp;rsquo;s a weird form of
xenophobia.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:4">
&lt;p>I bought Yusef Lateef&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Eastern Sounds&amp;rdquo; at Amoeba in LA.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:5">
&lt;p>With the exception of my girlfriend. I find that it is not uncommon for
expatriates in the US to feel like Americans do not have friends, there is
something really peculiar about how Americans deal with friendship.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:6">
&lt;p>If you are wondering, it&amp;rsquo;s Quarteto Novo&amp;rsquo;s self titled album.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:6" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Home</title><link>/posts/home/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 23:41:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/home/</guid><description>I grew up in a farm, a farm in the middle of nowhere. Well, of course it is somewhere, 22° 02′ 46.2″ S 43° 02′ 38.2″ W to be exact, it&amp;rsquo;s just that &amp;ldquo;where&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t the question to be asked, because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter because it could&amp;rsquo;ve been anywhere; I could&amp;rsquo;ve grown in a farm in China, Alabama, or France, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make much of a difference because those are just names; home is home.</description><content>&lt;p>I grew up in a farm, a farm in the middle of nowhere. Well, of course it is
somewhere, &lt;em>22° 02′ 46.2″ S 43° 02′ 38.2″ W&lt;/em> to be exact, it&amp;rsquo;s just that &amp;ldquo;where&amp;rdquo;
isn&amp;rsquo;t the question to be asked, because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter
because it could&amp;rsquo;ve been anywhere; I could&amp;rsquo;ve grown in a farm in China, Alabama,
or France, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t make much of a difference because those are just names;
home is home. Now, if you go on Google Earth and input the coordinates to my
home you&amp;rsquo;ll find a lake, and a somewhat desolate patch of land. Someone, you
see, decided my home was better suited as a lake for a dam; they gave us some
money, demolished it, and flooded it into oblivion. This also doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter
though, it&amp;rsquo;s not as if you had looked before it was gone you would have seen my
home; you would have seen a farm. Home isn&amp;rsquo;t a place on earth, it&amp;rsquo;s made of, and
lives in, memories; it&amp;rsquo;s eternally yours to visit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I visit home often. Not through the advent of technology, perhaps unfortunately
for they are clean and unopinionated, but through &lt;em>saudade&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s uncontrollable
and fierce, it stabs you in the heart with its invisible warn blade, and you
drift off into the known. I am laying down on the floor next to my girlfriend, a
deep breath, I am laying in the grassland behind the &lt;em>Jabuticaba&lt;/em> trees, a deep
breath, I am in a slowly rocking hammock, a deep breath, where am I? I&amp;rsquo;m in my
my girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s house, of course; she asks me what&amp;rsquo;s wrong; nothing&amp;rsquo;s wrong, I
was just visiting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I mentioned my teleportation device earlier, &lt;em>saudade&lt;/em>, but I tend to forget not
everyone knows it&amp;rsquo; name. The Portuguese, for all their failures, did succeed at
being the only ones to discover teleportation, or at least the only ones to name
it. Saudade is a notoriously untranslatable word; it is &amp;ldquo;longing, melancholy,
nostalgia, &amp;hellip; a vague and constant desire for something that does not, and
probably cannot exist, not an active discontent or poignant sadness, but an
indolent, dreaming wistfulness.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> Saudade is everything taking so long to be
so miserable, it fills the soul with lacking. As Drummond wrote, we also have
saudade of what hasn&amp;rsquo;t been, and it hurts a lot&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Saudade is raw power in
word-form; it is impossible for me to say it without getting goosebumps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The more I live and the more I accomplish, the more I realize that I am lost. I
am lost because I cannot find home; it no longer exists for me to find it. I can
point to it on the map, I can go to its exact location and wander around, I can
even stand at the exact location where my room used to be, and yet I am not
home. I may have found it on the map, but the truth is it remains lost. Home,
and to varying degrees this true for everyone, is an eternal entity of the past.
Being at &lt;em>22° 02′ 46.2″ S 43° 02′ 38.2″ W&lt;/em> had little bearing on the cathartic
entity that is home. When I visited the farm after the flooding, and I walked on
the few remaining pieces of land, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel much at all. I was mildly sad,
if anything, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a meaningful experience, I think. When I see my whole
family together, now in Rio de Janeiro, bickering and gossiping and talking
loudly; that&amp;rsquo;s when I miss home, that&amp;rsquo;s when the void of saudade feels like my
chest will collapse and I will disappear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This past-tense aspect of home, it&amp;rsquo;s existence being only virtual, is what makes
it so strong. In some ways, home is a common denominator between us all,
everyone has a home, somewhere in their memory. Home can disappear, and yet
remain within us for as long as we are alive. I oscillate between seeing this as
a curse or a blessing, because saudade of what can no longer exist hurts so
much. Thinking about this reminded me of David Byrne&amp;rsquo;s track [&amp;ldquo;Home,][home]&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>
where he sings:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You can fly - from the stuff that still surrounds you&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re home - and the band keeps marching on&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Connecting - to every living soul&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Compassion - for things I&amp;rsquo;ll never know&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The whole song, in one way or another, deals deeply with the idea of home, but I
think that passage, the ending of the track, speaks precisely of how home
permeates the human condition. Maybe what makes home so special is that it&amp;rsquo;s
existence is just sown in with our humanity. Maybe to be human is to have a home
and to long for it once it lives solely in memory. Perhaps the real wisdom to be
had is that we should all cherish home, while it lasts and once it&amp;rsquo;s gone, for
it&amp;rsquo;s part of what makes us human, for it&amp;rsquo;s part of who we are, always.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="memories-in-past-tense">Memories in Past Tense&lt;/h2>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="./images/flowers.jpg" />
&lt;/figure>
&lt;hr>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="./images/hall.jpg" />
&lt;/figure>
&lt;hr>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="./images/horse.jpg" />
&lt;/figure>
&lt;hr>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="./images/chickens.jpg" />
&lt;/figure>
&lt;hr>
&lt;figure class="left" >
&lt;img src="./images/entrance.jpg" />
&lt;/figure>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>Emmons, Shirlee and Lewis, Wilbur Watkins; &amp;ldquo;Researching the Song: A Lexicon&amp;rdquo;&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2">
&lt;p>Drummond, Carlos de Andrade; &amp;ldquo;O Avesso Das Coisas&amp;rdquo;&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:3">
&lt;p>Byrne, David; &amp;ldquo;Everything That Happens Will Happen Today&amp;rdquo;
[home]: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dC8Gxqhcjhk">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dC8Gxqhcjhk&lt;/a>&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></content></item></channel></rss>